Roderick Moise

Designer & Developer

W: rmoise.com E: roderickfmoise@gmail.com

Github: /rmoise Linkedin: /roderickmoise

A: Berlin, DE

Profile

From Brooklyn to Berlin, my career blends NYC ad agency experience with a passion for Bauhaus-inspired design. I recently completed a full-stack web development bootcamp at CareerFoundry, where I built my own website. I aim to create seamless, user-focused experiences.

Experience

2023 - Present

Full Stack Developer

Freelance Berlin, Germany

- Currently learning Next.js to expand my expertise in modern web development frameworks.
- · Currently optimizing a client's website using Sanity.io to ensure responsiveness and make components easily editable.
- Implemented a custom call log flow, enhancing data capture for client communications and reporting.

2023 - 2024

UI / UX Designer

KARL STORZ Berlin, Germany

- · Revamped the online catalog and checkout process with UX research and Figma prototyping, boosting engagement.
- Updated Salesforce email templates and landing pages for consistency and easier customization, enhancing branding.
- Redesigned and launched the website, aligning with the new design for improved engagement.

2019 - 2022

UI / Brand Designer

Kyto Berlin, Germany

- · Created a cohesive brand strategy for Kyto, a software as a service company, and new products.
- · Created new visual identity, including marketing materials and UI for web and mobile apps, ensuring brand consistency.
- · New branding, website, and mobile design boosted customer engagement, leading to Müller Medien acquisition.

Education

CareerFoundry

Full Stack Dev Certificate Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

Fashion Institute of Technology

BFA in Graphic Design Aug 2013 - May 2015 NY, NY

Languages

English: Native German: Beginner

Haitian Creole: Intermediate

Skills

Frontend	Backend	Tech Tools	Mobile & Apps	Design & UX
HTML/CSS JavaScript TypeScript Bootstrap React Angular Tailwind	Node.js Express C# ASP.NET PostgreSQL MongoDB AWS	Git AWS Firebase Heroku Netlify Postman Salesforce CRM	React Native PWA, Expo	Adobe CC Figma UI/UX Design Brand Identity Prototyping User Research Usability

Roderick Moise

Designer & Developer

W: rmoise.com E: roderickfmoise@gmail.com

Github: /rmoise Linkedin: /roderickmoise

A: Berlin, DE

Projects

2023 **Document Management App**

Personal Project

- Developed a React and ASP.NET Core document management app with upload, preview, sharing, using PostgreSQL and Azure Blob Storage.
- Added secure authentication and responsive design for all devices.
- Deployed on Azure, including user guides for easy adoption.

2023 **Meet App**

CareerFoundry

- Developed a PWA in React to display events from Google Calendar.
- Applied TDD with Jest (unit), Cucumber (acceptance), and Puppeteer (E2E) tests based on user stories.
- Implemented serverless functions using AWS Lambda and used a Kanban board to follow an agile process.

myFlix 2022

CareerFoundry

- Created a non-relational movie database (MongoDB) and built a REST API with Node.JS and Express.
- Tested the API endpoints with Postman, wrote clean and concise documentation, deployed the API with Heroku.
- · Designed and developed two single-page, responsive frontend applications using React and Angular.